...capacity accelerated much further.
Annual capacity exceeded 250 gigawatts,
reaching 3,891 gigawatts by the end of 2021.
The average annual growth rate for the past 15 years
is nearly 10%.
And this diagram shows the power capacity distribution in China.
Over the past 10 years, China's power installation mix has undergone a historic shift from fossil
energy dominance to green energy dominance.
The share of solar power installed capacity has dropped substantially, while no fossil
Also energy, particularly wind and solar power, has achieved explosive growth and become the core energy driving the green transition of energy structure.
You can get two conclusions from this diagram.
The first, the share of thermal power continuously decline.
Here I said the thermal power means cold power because in China the thermal power mainly is cold power.
You can see for the cold power fell from 67.3% in 2014 to 39.6% in 2035.
This marks a notable reduction in the power system's reliance on the power.
The second point is non-fossil energy becomes the mainstay.
The share of installed non-fossil energy capacity, including hydropower, solar power, wind power, and nuclear power,
Low steadily from 32.7% in 2014 to 40.4% in 2025, taking an outright leading position for the first time.
And this diagram shows the proportion of power generation in China in 2024.
And in the last slide, we know that coal power accounted for 43% of the total installed capacity.
Lower than 48% of new energy.
However, from this figure, we can find that coal power contributed about 63% of the total power generation.
1.8 times that of new energy power.
Which means in 2024, the installed capacity for coal power is only 43%,
but the power generation is about 63%.
Which means all the wind and solar power have registered rapid growth.
their utilization rates remain relatively low.
Hence, coal power remains the final safeguard for the secure operation of the power grid in China.
From the above data, we can get the conclusion that coal power still plays a very important role in China.
Therefore, this report focuses on the development and application of clinical power technology.
The development of clinical power technology has gone through three stages in China.
The 1970s to 1990s is the initial stage.
This is focused on post-combustion full-gas deseparation and dust removal technology to
address acid, rain, and dust pollution, leading the foundation for environmental governance.
You can find in this period for nitrogen oxide or NOx, there is no limitation, there is only
limitation standard for sox, silver oxides and dust. There is no limitation for sox.
The second stage is 2000 to 2010. It is the development stage. This stage shifted
towards improving power generation efficiency technologies such as
super-gradable power generation technology and multi-protein control
control technologies such as neutral low-emission technology.
The third stage is 2020 to present.
This stage is a deepening transformation stage.
It focuses on synergistic reduction of pollutants and carbon,
developing higher-efficiency technologies, flexibility
and integration with CCUS for low-carbon transition.
I use three sentences to summarize the China core position in China.
The first sentence is the best store for energy security.
China has built the world's largest clinical power system,
contributing 60% of power generation and 80% of peak shipping capacity.
It serves as a better storm for energy security and the stabilizer of the energy.
Second sentence is a green benchmark for fossil power.
By the end of 2025,
In 1975, over 95% of coal-fired power units in China had achieved neutral emissions, reaching
an international leading clean data.
The third is the power energy for low-carbon upgrade.
The average power supply co-consumption dropped to 301.6 grams per kilowatt in 2024, with
thermal efficiency exceeding 50% for the world's first 630 Celsius-degree ultrasonic critical
or USC unit.
Chinese government has released some key documents to provide policy guidance for clean coal power.
In this April, Chinese government issued opinions on energy conservation and carbon reduction.
This document emphasizes strengthening energy saving, carbon reducing, and flexibility retrofitting of coal power,
focusing on performance improvement of existing units.
Second document is the 15th Five-Year Plan for Modern Energy System.
It requires promoting clean and efficient utilization of coal and orderly reduction and substitution,
setting a target of reducing the average power supply coal consumption to below 300 grams per kilowatt by 2025.
The third document is an action plan for carbon peaking before 2030.
And this problem is related to the Chinese double carbon goals, the dual carbon goals.
I will talk about dual carbon goals in a moment.
This problem requires strictly controlling new coal power projects
projects, and promoting the triple retrofit energy-sealing, combined heat and power of
CHP, flexibility retrofit of existing units.
After the overview of the history, status, and supporting policies of China's clinical
sector, now we will move on to Chapter 2, where we will detail the key clinical power
technologies. Co-processing stages for clinical utilization include pre-, in- and after-combustion
treatment processes. Pre-combustion or before combustion, co-quality is improved from the
source through co-washing and co-blending technology. Co-washing technology can reduce
use ash and sulfur through washing processes,
China's low coal washing rate has reached 78.6% in 2020.
And coal blending technology, it can scientifically
blend different coal types for stable, efficient, and low
pollution combustion.
In combustion, or during combustion,
Low nitrogen combustion technology is used to inhibit pollutant formation.
Its principle is to inhibit nitrogen oxides, or NOx, formation through air staging, fuel staging, and low gas recirculation.
And its effect can reduce NOx concentration at boiler outlet to 200-300 mg per m3, reducing
the burden on subsequent SCR system post-combustion or after combustion.
Through a major combination of flue gas purification technologies, including SCR, denitrification,
wet desuferization, and high-efficiency dust removal, neutral emissions of pollutants are achieved.
These figures show pre-combustion technologies, including cold washing, cold blending, cold
brackets, and cold water slurry.
Its core principle is to remove ash and sulfur by physical and chemical cold washing to improve
cold quality, and mix different kinds of colds scientifically by cold blending to increase
with combustion emissions.
These have the advantages of improved efficiency.
It can stabilize coal quality, increase boiler combustion
efficiency greatly, reduce combustion fluctuations,
and clean emissions.
It can remove ash and sulfur from coal salts,
greatly reduce dust and salt emissions,
and reduce costs. It can blend low-price coal, optimize fuel structure, and reduce fuel costs effectively.
During combustion, low-NOx combustion technology constitutes the first line of defense for NOx emission control.
By adopting air staging and fuel staging methods combined with advanced low NOx burner, it can effectively inhibit NOx formation with an efficiency of more than 50%.
For the in-combustion, there are several practical methods.
First is air stage combustion.
Air-stage combustion is the stage-supply of combustion air into the furnace,
creates a fuel-rich, low-oxygen-reducing atmosphere in primary combustion soil,
inhibiting the formation of thermal knocks at the source.
And the second is fuel-stage combustion methods.
The secondary fuel, or reburning fuel, is injected downstream of the primary combustion
zone to form a storm reducing zone, which reduces the generated NOSGEN to harmless nitrogen.
The third is full gas recirculation, or FGR.
Extracted low temperature full gas is mixed with combustion air to reduce oxygen concentration
concentration and flame temperature in combustion zone, effectively suppressing thermal NOx
and block NOx.
And the evaporation effect can reduce NOx by 50% substantially, lowering treatment load
and operating costs of downstream denitrification facilities such as SCR facilities.
These are the two mainstream playing patterns for low nitrogen combustion.
The left is four-corner tangential finding, the right is front and rear wall-opposed finding.
For the left method, it's mainly used for the low volatile and low heating value code.
and for the front and rear finding is mainly for the high volatiles and high heating values.
Technology is circulating fluidized bed of deep CRP technology.
Its core principle lies in its unique circulating combustion method.
It has closed-loop system of combustion separation reflux recombustion
which greatly improves combating efficiency and fuel adaptability.
This kind of combating method brings four core advantages.
First is wide fuel adaptability, compatible with multiple fuel types.
Second is stable operation with wide load, adapting to great peak shipping.
because for CFB, its load regulation can be very wide, so it's adapting to a great big shift.
The third is integration in furnace, including desilverization, low cost and high efficiency.
The fourth is low temperature combustion inhibition,
Because for CEP boiler, its combustion temperature is relatively low compared to the power riser
cold boiler.
So its thermal NOx concentration is low.
So it has low NOx original emission.
This is CEP boiler principle and structure.
fuel and limestone is injected into the boiler's furnace.
In the boiler furnace, they are fluidized by the primary air from the draft fan.
And in the furnace, the coal, the fuel, is combusted completely.
and the ash is separated by the separator and returned back to the furnace.
Because in the boiler, it has a large amount of bad material,
and the material has a large amount of heat.
heat capacity. So the self-border is suitable for low heating value coal and high sulfur
For CF border, it can even combust some such as the solid waste, municipal solid waste.
And this is the CFB border and the power riser coil from Paris.
You can see from this table also the power riser coil has a high thermal efficiency.
its thermal efficiency is greater than 99%.
And for the thermal efficiency,
the combustion efficiency is greater than 99%.
And for the thermal efficiency, or power efficiency,
for neutral supercritical unit, it can be greater than 48%.
But for CM boiler, its combustion efficiency is 98%,
a little small, a little low than the parallelized coal.
And its power efficiency can reach 45%,
also a little low than the parallelized coal.
But for parallelized coal,
it usually combusts the high-quality coal.
But for CFE coal, it combusts the low-quality
or low-heating value coal.
And for the coal consumption,
consumption, because for coal consumption is related to the power efficiency. So, for
the power-wise coal, its thermal efficiency, power efficiency is high, so its coal consumption
is low. It's about 290 grams per kilowatt hour. While for the CF boiler, its coal consumption
is a little higher. It's about 312 grams per hour.
And for NOx emission, for power riser code, its NOx emission is
800 to 200 milligrams per meter cube.
Given that this is NOx concentration from the boiler
outlet, not from the power plant emission.
emission. And for self-boiler, because it is low nitrogen combustion, low nitrogen combustion,
so its noise emission at the boiler outlet is 200 milligrams per meter cube. Its high
efficiency in thermos desulfurization can reduce tail end fragility cost. It can reduce
the cost of desulfurization facility. So from this table we can find all the
polarized coal boilers are more efficient than burning high quality coal.
CMB boilers have obvious advantages in burning low quality coal. Pollutant
the levelized cost of energy for CFB is more competitive.
And for the load regulation and life cycle cost,
I forget to say just now.
For the parallelized code, its load regulation
is usually 50% to 100%.
But for the CFB, its load regulation is 30% to 110%,
which means it has better load regulation and it will be capital for the power grid.
China is a technology leader in CFE border field with world's largest market share,
especially achieving major breakthroughs in high parameter, high capacity of CFE technologies.
This figure, the right figure, is the Pingshuo CRB Power Plant, located in Shanxi province,
which is the world's first 660 megawatt CRB unit.
Next core technology is neutral supercritical technology.
Its core principle is to break through efficiency bottlenecks
By increasing steam parameters breaking critical point, we know for the critical point, its
critical pressure is 22 megapascals, and its critical temperature is 374 Celsius degrees.
Both temperature and pressure increases bring efficiency gains, this temperature having
a more significant impact.
This chart, the right chart, shows the trend of efficiency improvement under different
parameters, clearly indicating that higher parameters is the inevitable direction of
technology development.
From the right chart, we can find when they increase the temperature, this is the mixing
temperature from 600 degree and this is the reheat temperature, this is the misting temperature.
When we increase the misting temperature from 600 degree to 700 degree, the power efficiency
efficiency can reach about 5-6%. That's why for the ultra-supercritical power plant, we
will develop 700 temperature-misting Bitcoin, 700 plants in China. Then we increase the
pressure, misting pressure. The horizontal axis is the misting pressure. When we increase
the misting pressure, the power efficiency also increases, but it increases, it's a little
small. It's a little small, not like the temperature, it is very obvious.
years. Okay, compared to conventional supercritical unit,
usual supercritical unit has a higher steam pressure and steam
temperature. For conventional supercritical unit, its main
steam pressure is between 23 to 27 MPa, and main steam
temperature is between 540 to 560 Celsius degrees. But for
For neutral supercritical unit, it's main steam pressure is greater than 27 mPa.
And it's main steam temperature is between 508 to 600 degrees.
And for conventional supercritical, it's power efficiency is about 2% higher than subcritical unit.
and co-consumption is between 290 to 300 grams per kilowatt-hour.
However, for neutral supercritical unit, our efficiency is about 5% higher than subcritical unit,
and co-consumption is between 270 to 280 grams per kilowatt-hour.
U-turn supercritical technology is currently the most efficient clean coal power generation technology.
China has the world's largest application scale in this field and continues to lead in technology.
By the end of 2024, installed capacity of U-SC units exceeded 320 GW,
accounting for nearly 60% of the total coal-fired power plants in China.
In June, the world's first 630°C double reheat USC million kilowatt units was put into operation
with power generation efficiency exceeding 50% for the first time
is setting a new world record.
Next technology is deep peaking technology.
Peak shielding technology is through the technical retrofits.
The minimum operating load limit of generating units can be overcome.
Units can maintain stable combustion and safe operating
operating under operation conditions of 20% to 50% rated power, efficiency including unit
flexibility and peak shearing capacity.
By comprehensive retrofits of boiler, steam turbine, thermal power decoupling system and
control system, units can operate stably at lower loads.
This enabled them to better accommodate power grid fluctuations and create room for the
integration of new engines such as wind and solar power.
By the end of 2024, China has completed flexibility retrofits for coal-fired generating units
with a total capacity of 210 gigawatts, which has greatly enhanced the power system's peak
shipping capacity.
For policy orientation, implement the requirement of retrofitting all eligible units, promote
co-fired power from main power source to regulating power source, and support achievement of dual
carbon goals.
Next, we enter chapter 3, where I will introduce several advanced technologies for clean coal
power generation, including neutral low-emission technology, CCUS technology, ORC technology,
coal power integrated with renewable energy technology.
The first advanced technology is flue gas neutral low-emission technology, which has
has been widely popularized in China.
It's not a single technology, but a set of combined processes,
from the low nitrogen combustion inside boiler,
to SCR denitrification, to high efficiency dust removal
technology, to wet flue gas desuparization,
and finally is the wet electrostatic precipitator.
And by this series of methods, a completely pollutant control chain is formed
to ensure emission and strict pollutant standards.
And the effect of neutral low emission transformation is remarkable.
This table shows the pollutant standard in 2004 and 2012.
This is the 2004 standard, and this is the 2012 standard,
and this is the newest emissions standard in China now.
It's still in effect.
Okay, you can see the change of dust, sulfur, it should be sulfur oxides, nitrogen oxides.
For 2004 standard, its dust indication is 50 milligram per meter cube for the new power plant,
for new power plant, and this is for the old power plant, it's 200.
And for silver oxides, its emission is 400 mg per m3 for the new power plant,
1200 for old power plant, NOx is 450 for new power plant, and 1100 for the old power plant.
Well, for the 212 standard, you can find the emission limitation has been decreased greatly.
Decreased greatly, which means it has a very strict standard.
For the dust, its limitation is 20 mg per m3,
for the clean regions such as Peking, Shanghai, Hebei province.
and 30 for other regions, and for NOx, sulfur oxide is 50 for K regions and 200 for other regions.
For NOx, it's 100 for K regions and 200 for other regions.
And for the investment cost, the neutral emission retrofit for a single 600 megawatt unit costs
about 150 to 250 million CNY, Chinese money, CNY.
And for the life cycle cost, inside SCR catalysts with replacement,
de-supervisor consumption, and station service power.
For economic, social benefits, intelligent virtual feeding can reduce environmental chemical consumption by 8 to 15%.
Chinese government has issued dual carbon goals, carbon peaking and carbon neutrality.
Carbon peaking before 2030 and carbon neutrality before 2060.
The roadmap is divided into three stages.
First, from 2021 to 2030, we achieved carbon peaking.
From 31 to 45, rapid reduced carbon emissions.
From 46 to 60, deep decarbonization of carbon neutrality.
And key measures to achieve the dual carbon goals include
includes clean and efficient utilization of coal in the power industry,
develop new and renewable energy sources,
carbon reduction retrofits in key industries and fields,
and last is carbon capture utilization and storage technology, or CCUS technology.
CCUS technology is a key technology on the path to achieve geocarbon growth.
It mainly has three paths.
The first is post-combustion capture.
This capacity is the most major.
It directly separates carbon dioxide from the fuel gas
with a simple process and easy transformation of achieved plants.
The second is pre-combustion capture.
First, gasified fuels provide thin gas, then generate high concentration of carbon oxides.
Its concentration is 30 to 60 percent, and hydrogen reduces carbon dioxide separation
energy consumption, such as the ICCC technology belongs to this method, belongs to the gray
And this method has higher capacity, but it also has disadvantages, its investment cost
is very huge.
The last is oxygen fuel conductor, it uses pure oxygen fuel conductor, you get this kind
carbon dioxide and vapour, yielding high percentage of carbon dioxide after condensation.
This method also has a disadvantage of huge investment cost.
Each part has its own advantages and disadvantages and need to be selected according to specific conditions.
And this diagram shows the four technical frameworks of CCQS, including carbon dioxide
source, capture, storage, utilization, and composition.
First, carbon dioxide is produced from various emission sources, such as the power plant,
such as the nature, such as the air, such as from the vehicle.
Then carbon dioxide is captured and separated by multi-technologies such as chemical absorption, physical absorption, and biological method.
After capture, carbon dioxide has two major directions, geological storage or further utilization.
After capture, the carbon dioxide concentration is increased by two methods.
First is storage, storage in the geologic deep sea or sea-line layer.
Next is physical utilization and conversion, chemical conversion.
And for these two methods, we can use carbon dioxide for some products such as fuels, encodes, and carbonates.
Neutral emission technologies and CCUS technologies are the key to achieving near zero emissions from coal power by the end of 2024.
24, or 1,050 gigawatts of co-fired power units in China
has been graduated, accounting for over 94% in service units.
And the right figure is the Chinese Zhening Power Plant.
This parkland is located in the Shaanxi province.
This project has been the world's largest coal-fired power carbon capture project,
with an annual capture capacity of 1.5 million tonnes.
But the high cost remains the main challenge for its promotion.
ORC technology is a waste heat recovery technology.
It uses special organic co-working fluids to convert medium and low temperature waste,
such as exhaust gas from power plants and heat from circulating water.
It has a simple system and the technology is safe and reliable.
It is a power tool to improve energy utilization efficiency.
All these core technical advantages include low temperature adaptability, high energy utilization efficiency,
it can effectively utilize low-grade waste heat resources and greatly improve the compressive energy recovery rate.
And this table compares the ORC technology with traditional steam cycle technology.
Traditional steam cycle technology such as the power plant technology is the traditional steam technology.
From this table we can see for the steam cycle, for steam cycle is habitable heat source is
high temperature source is usually greater than 400 degree.
And for organic cycle, its heat source is low or medium temperature source, its temperature
between 90 degrees to 400 degrees. So it has a wide range of heat sources.
And the system characteristics, for steam cycle, it is high pressure, it has large air
on pipe. And for the organic cycle, it is low pressure, and it is compact, and it is
modular and for the resource consumption for steam cycle it must use the water so it must have the
water supply because there is high water consumption and for the organic cycle there
is no water consumption so it can use air cooling air cooling method so for the organic
In the organic cycle, it can be applied in different scenarios, such as industrial waste heat recovery for blue gas and circulating water.
It can also be applied in some marine engineering, such as the wind tunnel of fuel for the waste utilization.
The integration of coal power with renewable energy is an important direction for future
energy development.
Through various models such as wind-coal storage integration, flexibility retrofitting,
multi-energy integration, and green hydrogen carbon, coal power can be set up to play its regulatory role and have built a more stable and low-carbon neon power system.
This project, the LIFE project, is the peaking shearing coal-fired power supporting the large-scale
new energy in the Baden Desert, located in Shanxi Province in western China.
It contains four 1,000 megawatt high-efficiency neutral supercritical coal-fired power plants
with deep peak shielding capability to accommodate local wind energy and solar energy.
And this diagram shows a typical integrated energy system including PV, wind power, fuel cell and gas boiler as energy sources,
PCS and batteries realize energy storage while EMS optimizes the whole system's electric heating, cooling, gas, and transformation loads.
For this integrated energy system that has multiple energy supply,
This is wind power, this is solar power, and this is fuel cell, this is thermal power boiler.
And it's up that products also include multiple products, including electricity, heating,
cooling, gas, and for the recharge of some vehicles.
Okay, next is the last chapter, conclusion and suggestion.
We will analyze industrial hot stores, costs, and policies, and put forward strategic outlook.
look for the cost and investment for new built units the investment suggestion in
neutral supercritical units is about 4 000 cmy per kilowatt with the best economic efficiency
and for retrofit projects the flexibility retrofit cost is about 30 to 90 cmy per kilowatt
In fact, the CCUS benefit cost is the highest, highly dependent on policy incentives.
And for policy incentive safety, for existing safety, we've adopted mandatory standards,
financial support, green finance, and market-based mechanisms.
For future improvements, to improve the capacity price mechanism, improve the energy service
market, stretching carbon market incentives, and for the strategic action guidelines, include
deepening transformation and upgrading, focus on core technologies, promote energy hub transformation,
steaming steaming days and generous motivation strengthen international cooperation and the
current hotspots and outlook for green coal power technology are mainly reflected in four aspects
first the demand for flexibility enhancement the second the integration of CCUS technology
technology for deep decarbonization, third, the transformation for coal-fired power plants
into integrated energy service, and finally, improving operation efficiencies through intelligence
and digitalization.
Okay.
That's all for my report.
Thank you for your attention.
Question?